

## AI ALGORITHM ENGINEER

Contact Info



+886 0923550217



jaihuayen@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.co m/in/jai-hua-yenba455990/

# **JAI-HUA YEN**

# 顏嘉華

I am a highly-motivated, fast-learning, and innovative professional that specialized and have a high interest in data science with about one year experience in industry and two-year experience in academics. I am currently an AI Algorithm Engineer in TutorABC, where I integrate my skills in AI and statistics to give deeper inference in different prospective on business data.

### PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

### AI ALGORITHM ENGINEER

TUTORABC | MAY 2020 - PRESENT

### (1) Artificial Intelligence:

- Apply computer vision (yolov3) to consumer's responses (hand detection with 90% accuracy) and company services (OCR) to improve user experience.
- Build recommendation system by Bert and FastAPI and use it as the response of Line chatbot.
- Improve the quality of the matching system between our customers and products by performing classification (k-means) of the contents of our educational materials (TFIDF & Bert Embedding).

### (2) Data Analytics:

- Design products based on the information of grouped customer features using factor analysis.
- Build interactive dashboards and give data insights for stakeholders using SQL and Metabase.
- Construct a refund model to lower the refund rate by implementing feature extraction and decision tree model.

### (3) Data Engineering:

- Construct Shiny Dashboard and Shiny Server by Docker for producing interactive dashboards for stakeholders and BI tool for data analytics usage.
- Build AI chatbot system under Docker, which make AI product much easier to reproduce.

### NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY

MS BIOMETRY & BIOINFORMATICS, 2017-2019

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

• Thesis: Richness estimation with the presence of species identity error.

### NATIONAL TSING UNIVERSITY

BS QUANTITATIVE FINANCE, 2017-2019

• Certificate in Data Science issued from Institute of Statistics.

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

• Programming: R, Python, MSSQL, MATLAB, SAS, C++

• Others: Linux, Docker, Git

### PUBLICATION

Yen, J.-H., Chiu, C.-H. (2020). Richness estimation with species identity error. *Proceedings 62th InternationalStatistical Institute (ISI)*World Statistics Congress, Volume 6, 401-408.

### TALKS

- Contributed Speaker, The 62th International Statistical Institute World Statistics
  Congress, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. August 21, 2019.
- Lecturer, Teaching Assistant Training Seminar, Taipei Medical University, Taipei City, Taiwan. February 26, 2019.
- Lecturer, 2019 Teaching Assistant Training Seminar, National Taiwan University, Taipei City, Taiwan. February 15, 2019.

### AWARDS

- Excellent Teaching Assistant Award, National Taiwan University, Dec. 2018.
- Taekwondo Competition Bronze Medal, Hungkuang University, Oct. 2017.
- Karate Competition Gold Medal, Neihu Senior High School, Jan. 2012.

## Contact Info



+886 0923550217



jaihuayen@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.co m/in/jai-hua-yenba455990/